

#### **Laura Uribe**

## **Career Summary**

Data Engineer with three years of experience in analyzing large data sets and coming up with data-driven insights for early-stage technology companies using SQL databases, python, pyspark and low code tools (Microsoft power apps, Azure Logic apps and Azure DataFactory) with teams of 3-15 members.

# **Summary of Qualifications**

#### Proficient in:

- Python
- SQL
- Azure Cloud
- Azure Synapse Analytics
- Azure Databricks

- SQL Server
- MySQL
- Azure DataFactory (integration runtime, triggers, linked services, datafows, pipelines, etc)
- Git/Github
- Azure DataLake

- Azure Blob Storage
- Azure Logic apps/ Azure functions

# Languages

- Spanish (native C2)
- English (advanced- B2)

• French (intermediate - B1)

### **Career History**

### **CEMENTOS ARGOS S.A, Medellín, Colombia**

Data Engineer Smart Pricing Calculator

Apr. 2021 - Present

#### Responsibilities:

- Redesign connection flow with Command Alkon, Salesforce and Azure.
- Support connection flow with Command Alkon, Salesforce and Azure.
- Built an anomaly model to monitor sales prices of concrete in the USA.

Tools/Technologies: SQL Server, Azure Datafactory, Azure DataLake.

Continuous improvement

#### Responsibilities:

- Built an ETL process to provide relevant data to a consulting company (Deloitte) which helped us create models for our own use.
  - Design connection flow with SAP ERP and Azure.
  - Support connection flow with SAP ERP and Azure.



Tools/Technologies: Xtract Universal, Azure DataFactory, Azure DataLake

### UNIVERSIDAD DE ANTIOQUIA, Medellín, Colombia

Una arquitectura de información para los estudios de cohorte en epidemiología ambiental

Jul. 2021 – Apr. 2022

## Responsibilities:

- Design the Data Warehouse of a cohort study in environmental epidemiology
- Support in encryption of confidencial information

Tools/Technologies: MySQL Workbench, Python, Git/Github

# MGM INNOVA ENERGY SERVICES S.A, Medellín, Colombia

Support Engineer

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2020

#### Responsibilities:

- Built dashboard using data from a Schneider equipment to monitor intraday energy consumption equipment to monitor intraday energy consumption.
- Create monitoring protocol for electrical equipment in a hotel.
- Built report of maintenance of critical equipment such as air conditioners an boilers to prevent damage.

Tools/Technologies: Python, Excel, Google Data Studio

#### **Education**

**UNAL, Medellín, Colombia**MSc of Engineering Data Analytics

Jun. 2020 – Dec. 2022

**UdeM, Medellín, Colombia** BS of Energy Engineering Jul. 2014 - Dec. 2019